FULL STACK ENGINEER WITH 7 YEARS OF PROGRAMMING EXPERIENCE

My Personal Portfolio demonstrates the skill set I have acquired over the last seven years.



Software Engineer With Seven Years of Programming Experience

Phone: +1 (210) 585-6279 Email: dreebarrera@gmail.com Austin, Texas, USA

www.drebarrera.com



in www.linkedin.com/in/drebarrera/



www.github.com/drebarrera

EDUCATION

BSE in Computer Engineering Purdue University | 2022

FEATURED CERTIFICATIONS

Udemy Next.js & React - The Complete Guide

MongoDB Python Development **AWS Technical Essentials Certification** Udemy Golang Course Certification

LANGUAGES

C & C++, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Dart, Golang, PHP, SQL, Java, Assembly, Verilog, MATLAB

FRAMEWORKS

React, Next.js, Node.js, Angular, Flutter, TailwindCSS, SassCSS, Bootstrap, Amazon Web Services (AWS), MySQL, MongoDB, WordPress, Prometheus, Grafana, Selenium, Chrome Extensions, RTI DDS, VBA, SQL, NoSQL, JSON & API Development, Docker, Wix, Figma, Photoshop, SVG, Semrush, YoastSEO, and many more!

See my Manifesto for more information.

RECENT WORK EXPERIENCE



June 2024 - August 2024

Software Engineer Contractor

Developing the next generation of data visualization with a small Austin startup. Sprouty leverages a microserviced cloud model to produce a lightweight desktop application for creating and managing data, APIs, automation, and interfaces.

Skills: Golang, Node.js, Express.js, TypeScript, Flutter, Dart, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, MySQL, Selenium



December 2023 - August 2024

Software Engineer Contractor | Consultant

Developing web applications and supporting backend infrastructure for a startup dedicated to creating a safer digital dating scene.

Skills: Angular, SassCSS, Bootstrap, Docker, Java Spring, Java, Figma, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JS, WordPress, Flutter, Dart, YoastSEO, Semrush



May 2023 - Current

President | Software Engineer

Leading and developing content for a non-profit dedicated to elevating the Latino tech community. Read the Case Study.

Skills: Leadership, Next.js, React, TailwindCSS, Figma, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Adobe Photoshop



June 2022 - July 2023

Software Engineer

Defense Software Modernization: Modernizing the US Navy's tactical weapons system. Read the Case Study.

EV Systems Architecture: Designing R&D circuits and firmware for the next generation of electric vehicles. Read the <u>Case Study</u>.

Skills: C++, Python, React, Node.js, Docker, Prometheus, Grafana, RTI DDS, GitHub, Linux, Draw.io, KiCAD, Beagle Board, Arduino, Linux, Texas Instruments, Nordic, Solidworks, Draw.io, Adafruit, GitHub

SUMMARY

I have devoted my educational and professional life to developing efficient code, designing beautiful content, and engineering next generation products.

Long-Term Dedication

In middle school and high school, I would dedicate my recess time to developing websites and creating programming tutorial videos for my classmates.

Community Oriented

I am a strong advocate for the Latino community, leading a non-profit organization and representing my heritage. Our organization, Hispanic Hackers, aims to democratize the tech industry for Latinos, with 2,500 members from different backgrounds.

Avid Polyglot

Not only do I program in almost a dozen different languages, but I also speak 5 and read 6 more! I am always happy to chat with you in fluent English or Spanish or elementary level Japanese, German, or Russian. I can also write and read Hiragana, Katakana, Kanji, Cyrillc, Korean, and Hebrew.

Happy to Take On a Challenge

In my free time, I climb mountains (most recently the Tsurumidake and Yufudake volcanoes in Japan), write music, run, and enjoy nature. I never shy away from a challenge and often take on projects outside of the realm of technology!



August 2021 - December 2022

Frontend Engineer

Building website and brand content for a startup which takes drone footage to new heights. Read the <u>Case Study</u>.

Skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Python, Wix, Adobe Photoshop, Final Cut Pro



August 2020 - December 2020

Engineering Intern

Engineering Intern for a company which assesses industrial liner integrity using high voltage injection techniques. Designed, built, and programmed electrical prototypes and firmware for the next generation of equipment. Conducted research on the use of high voltage systems to create 3-dimensional models.

Skills: C++, Python, Numpy, Matplotlib, MATLAB, Electrical Drafting, PCB Design, Electrical Construction



June 2016 - August 2021

Developer | Technology Consultant

Consultant to the family practice, Texas Center for Facial Plastic Surgery and ENT. Assisted in the development of the company website and initiated a Selenium Python data-scraping project to assist ABM Marketing agency with their development of Shopify marketplace site. Developed my first API to transfer customer marketing data. Designed marketing content and supported technology operations.

Skills: Python, Selenium, PHP, JavaScript, Node.js, HTML, CSS, WordPress, Shopify